Maria Angelica Marinelli

El Cajon, California | +1 2025940418 | mariaangelicamarinelli@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mariaangelicamarinelli

Human Resources

Self-taught student in Software Engineering and Web Development, focus on Python, HTML, CSS, C++, Bootstrap 4, Javascript and React. Former Elementary School Teacher and English Teacher ESL in Brazil, with experience in English and Portuguese Linguistics and English Literature, 7 years of experience in Education field.

Currently taking the course Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) - Onward to Opportunity - at Syracuse University, IVMF

- Translation
- Customer Management
- Brazilian Portuguese
- Management
- Leadership
- Community Engagement
- Teaching
- Linguistics
- Microsoft Office Applications

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Caregiver, Self-employed

08/2020 - Present

- Gained valuable communication and negotiating skills for diplomatically raising concerns with my employers.
- Problem-solving skills to successfully deal with everyday issues that inevitably occur.
- Honed skills of communication, time-management and problem-solving.
- Organize creative activities and educational games.

AuPair - Exchange Program, Au Pair in America

07/2019 - 08/2020

- Assisted children with daily activities including homework and extracurricular engagements.
- Developed and maintained a daily schedule, including educational activities.
- Coordinated various activities, resolved any problematic issues, and assisted kids in the development of fundamental learning skills.
- Adaptability skills by being in the exchange program while living with a host family.

Elementary School Teacher, Brazil

02/2018 - 07/2019

- Responsible for monitoring each student's progress and providing extra mentorship to those who need it.
- Giving and grading assignments, homework and tests.
- Overseeing students during recess, lunch and other activities.
- Meeting and working with other teachers and supervisors to discuss school policies.

English Teacher ESL, Brazil

06/2017 - 07/2019

- Conducted lesson plans to help teach and explain the English language to native Portuguese speakers.
- Utilized effective classroom management techniques by incorporating motivational activities and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Created a supportive and positive classroom environment.
- Resolved crises in the classroom.
- Collaborated with educational staff to provide a positive learning experience to students.
- Administrative tasks, such as keeping student registers and attendance records.

English Teacher ESL - Apprenticeship, Brazil

01/2016 - 06/2017

- Planned, prepared, and taught English lessons, promoting the general progress and well-being of individual students and groups of students.
- Taught grammar and syntax, vocabulary and word usage and other principles of the English language.
- Developed strategic plans for optimized productivity.
- Managed and delegated responsibilities to the best-qualified employees and enforced all policies, procedures, standards, specifications, guidelines, training programs, and cultural values.
- Managed the program's social media, with the aim of creating posts, advertising classes and courses. Managed interactions with the public by implementing social media platforms' content strategies.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Language Arts in English Linguistics and English Literature. Minor Portuguese Linguistics Universidade Federal de Uberlandia, Brazil

Software Engineer Prep Course - Python | Hackbright Academy English Program | LADO Institute

Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM) | Expected graduation 01/2023 | IVMF, Syracuse University